Opeyemi Okuboyejo

Plot 15, Block 11, Asero Estate, Abeokuta, Ogun State, Nigeria

Email: okuboyejoopeyemi01@gmail.com

Phone: +234-803-502-3882

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/opeyemi-okuboyejo

Profile Summary

Opeyemi is an AWS Certified Solutions Architect with competence, confidence, and credibility with practical cloud skills in AWS Cloud technology, across a wide range of AWS services. Using architectural design principles, he demonstrates the ability to strategically design well-architected distributed systems that are scalable, resilient, efficient, and fault-tolerant.

He demonstrates extensive experience in Microsoft technologies, servers, PCs, and other technology solutions from leading hardware and software vendors; he is Microsoft certified and has successfully implemented Microsoft and other business solutions for medium to large-scale organizations.

With over 15 years of industry experience and a sound technical foundation in IT, Opeyemi combines skills such as cloud virtualization, Kubernetes/Docker, web server management, systems administration, network administration, database administration to be a well-rounded and experienced IT Professional. When not working on IT projects, Opeyemi loves to explore his passion for learning by researching new and emerging trends as he tries out various web & cloud-based services and products while rapidly

Opeyemi also loves to teach, mentor, or provide guidance to others; a task that requires patience and people management skills. He needs no supervision having been a self-starter entrepreneur and team leader that earned the trust and confidence of clients for many years.

Skills, Tools & Technologies

 Cloud Services – AWS EC2, LightSail, Google Cloud Platform, Azure

learning new approaches to achieving great things.

- Windows Server & Desktop
- Kubernetes
- Docker
- Networking: LAN, VLAN WAN, Wireless
- Firewall, OpenVPN Server
- Databases MySQL, PhpMyAdmin
- Training & Mentoring
- Website Design & Management WordPress, Domain, Hosting

- Linux Administration
- Microsoft Office
- Virtualization VMWare, Hyper-V, VirtualBox
- Virtual Desktop Infrastructure (VDI, Thin-Clients)
- Linux Web Hosting Management (Apache, Webmin/Virtualmin)
- Email Server Configuration (Mautic, Amazon SES, SMTP

Professional Work Experience

Three Rings Integrity Systems (TRIS) – 05/2007 – 05/2017, 2020 – date

Technical Support, Systems Engineer, Network Engineer

- Three Rings Integrity Systems is an IT service company that provides IT services to small, medium, and large businesses.
- Working with a wide range of clients, and based on my hands-on practical knowledge of the AWS platform, I provide web hosting, server setup and configuration using Apache, Webmin/Virtualmin hosted on AWS EC2 Linux Compute and AWS LightSail instances. For small businesses without an in-house IT team, I provide technical IT support, website design & development services and self-hosted email marketing solutions for email marketing clients. Clients are supported through various means including break-fix, proactive managed support and engagement with principal stakeholders to determine business direction and propose/implement technical solutions that support their business outcomes and generally reduce their overall running cost.
- As a Systems Engineer and Technical Support, I regularly relate directly with clients to resolve various challenges with their PCs ranging from hardware faults to software crashes and general interconnectivity issues that arise from day-to-day business needs and usage of personal computers (including Laptops and Desktops) both in-house and onsite. I was also responsible for procuring suitable and appropriate computer systems for both individuals and organizations based on my professional recommendations over a period of 8+ years as a Systems Engineer.
- As part of mentoring initiatives, I led several initiatives targeted at developing IT skills in the
 community and providing internship, IT training and development for young graduates and
 college students transiting to universities. This scheme provided easy access to a pool of
 resources for meeting client needs as well as helped more than 20 young graduates to become
 self-reliant and employable.

SunPoint IT Solutions – 10/2019 – 04/2020

Remote Support Engineer (Managed IT Services)

- SunPoint IT Solutions is a growing Managed Services Provider (MSP) based in the San Francisco Bay area.
- Using Datto's Autotask Professional Services Automation (PSA) and Remote Monitoring and management (RMM) tools, I remotely administer solutions to support tickets raised ensuring client's business process has minimum interruption.

Peter Akinola Foundation (PAF) Youth Centre for Industrial Training – 05/2018 – 2019

Admin, IT Operations & Quality Assurance Manager

- The PAF Youth Centre is a Technical and Vocational Education Training (TVET) Centre for youth development.
- As Admin & IT Operations Manager, I worked alongside the leadership team and other management staff to define the day-to-day operations of the PAF Youth Centre from an information technology standpoint implementing and managing the technology stack that

supports the operations of the Centre. These included the internal systems – rack server, thinclients & PCs, projectors as well as external vendor-supplied systems like internet and telephone. I also defined security baseline for the servers and implemented them through patching and monitoring of network devices. Managing the entire infrastructure resulted in moving the PAF TVET Center form an unstable, unproductive system to one that was able to serve the needs of over 100 users. This had always been a challenge before I joined the PAF team.

Various Positions in Early Career – 1999 – 2006

 Field Engineer, Café Network Administrator, Computer Instructor/Tutor, Computer Repair Technician

Certifications & Trainings

- AWS Solutions Architect Associate (SAA)
- Microsoft Certified Professional (MCP)
- Microsoft Certified Systems Administrator (MCSA)
- Microsoft Certified Database Administrator (MCDBA)
- London City & Guilds Institute Level 3 IVQ Advanced Diploma in Teaching, Training and Assessing Learning

Education

- Master of Information Technology (MIT) LAUTECH 2014
- Post-Graduate Diploma (PgD) in Computer Science LAUTECH 2011
- Higher National Diploma (HND) in Electronics Engineering YABATECH 2004
- Certificate in Network Engineering